Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection AD.MC.002
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971 (Box 1-7)
  - A group portrait of men outdoors, two men wear uniforms. 19.6 x 25.6 cm, Undated; cuid1342; Albatrawi (Egypt) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Uniforms; Egypt; Turbans; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Canes/Walking Sticks; Regional/National Dress; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Men; Group Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Palm Trees; Military/Soldiers; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - The annual meeting for the Egyptian pharmacists association 19.5 x 25.9 cm, 1928; cuid1343 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; English Writing; Fez/Tarboush; Canes/Walking Sticks; Buildings; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Men; Doors/Entrances; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A group portrait of students and their teachers in suits, at the entrance to a building. 20.2 x 25.2 cm, 1923-1924; cuid1344 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Egypt; Doors/Entrances; Fez/Tarboush; Boys; Buildings; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Children; Hats
  - A group portrait of men mostly in suits. One man is holding an umbrella. 21.8 x 27.3 cm, 1926; cuid1345 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Turbans; Fez/Tarboush; Regional/National Dress; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Arabic Writing; Alexandria, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Umbrellas/Parasols; Men; Studio Photography; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A group portrait of men and one boy. Two men are seated on the ground. (studio stamp separated). 21.5 x 27.5 cm, Undated; cuid1346 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Children; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Buildings; Egypt; Mansoura, Egypt; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Arabic Writing; Hats
  - A group portrait of men. one holds a riding whip. Decorative border around photograph. 20.6 x 30.3 cm, 1 June 1912; cuid1347 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Facial Hair; Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Police; Men; Canes/Walking Sticks; Studio Photography; Uniforms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Military/Soldiers
  - A group portrait of men, some in regional dress and some in suits. A banner with a Quranic text hangs behind them at the "Preserving of the Quran" association meeting. 24.0 x 30.4 cm, Circa 1923-1952; cuid1348 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Hats; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Religious Imagery; Fez/Tarboush; Photographic Prints; Arabic Calligraphy; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Minya, Egypt; Quran/Koran; Carpets/Rugs; Turbans; Flags; Canes/Walking Sticks; Associations/Societies/Organizations; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Medals/Insignia; Facial Hair
  - A group portrait of men in front of a building, one man wears a uniform. 25.7 x 31.7 cm, Undated; cuid1349 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Regional/National Dress; Fez/Tarboush; Uniforms; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Doors/Entrances; Bow Ties; Men; Egypt; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Doors/Entrances; Canes/Walking Sticks; Facial Hair; Military/Soldiers; Hats
  - A group portrait of men, some wearing berets. 28.0 x 33.7 cm, Undated; cuid1350 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Men; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Hats; Outdoors; Regional/National Dress; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - School Portrait - A group of men with children, mostly boys in a workshop. 30.0 x 33.6 cm, Undated; cuid1283 (Box 7, Folder 12, Oversize unknown container)
    Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Men; Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Teachers; Students; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Facial Hair; Hats
  - School Portrait - A children's nursery class in Rod Al Farag. Arabic text on front: "Studio Sami, member of the Art Photographers Union in the Egyptian Kingdom. 27.0 x 27.5 cm, 1950-1951; cuid1284 (Box 7, Folder 12, Oversize unknown container)
    Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Schools/Education; Children; Girls; Boys; Kindergartens/Nurseries; Students; Choubra/Shubra, Egypt
  - School Portrait - A group of school aged boys of varying ages, posing in front of a building with a few adult men. 35.9 x 41.9 cm, Undated; cuid1285 (Box 7, Folder 12, Oversize unknown container)
    Cairo, Egypt; Teachers; Students; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Children; Schools/Education; Group Portraits; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Boys; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - School Portrait - Young women of varying ages in school uniforms standing in front of a building with wooden shutters (same building from ref1321). 23.5 x 30.0 cm, Undated; cuid1286 (Box 7, Folder 12, Oversize unknown container)
    Buildings; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Students; Furnishings; Egypt; Uniforms; Girls; Group Portraits; Children; Women; Men; Children; Carpets/Rugs
  - A group portrait of men with a dog. 29.0 x 34.3 cm, Undated; cuid1351 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Dogs; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Animals; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Regional/National Dress; Uniforms; Buildings; Egypt; Men; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Outdoors; Military/Soldiers; Hats
  - A group portrait of men posing in front of a building, some wear uniforms. Text on reverse: celebrating the appointment of the new Director/officer in charge of the center Kamal Beih Hussein. 28.0 x 35.1 cm, 6-3-1935; cuid1352 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Regional/National Dress; Buildings; Doors/Entrances; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Officials; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Fez/Tarboush; Outdoors; Carpets/Rugs; Turbans; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Hats
  - A group portrait of men in a garden.27.9 x 34.8 cm, Undated; cuid1353; A. Gaddis & G. Seif, Luxor (Egypt) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Luxor, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Group Portraits; Men; Egypt; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - The board of directors of the Orthodox Coptic charity association. 28.7 x 35.6 cm, 27 May 1945; cuid1354 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Egypt; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Outdoors; Fez/Tarboush; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Bow Ties; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A group portrait of men wearing medals, with a football placed on the floor (linked ref1378). 29.7 x 34.1 cm, Undated; cuid1355 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Medals/Insignia; Football; Sports; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Football; Studio Photography; Group Portraits; Men; Cairo, Egypt; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A group portrait of men in suits posing against a painted backdrop. 29.3 x 35.4 cm, 15 April 1929; cuid1356 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Egypt; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Group Portraits; Bow Ties; Painted Backdrops; Signatures; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A group portrait of men pose in a room with patterned wallpaper (linked ref1376). 29.7 x 34.2 cm, Undated; cuid1357 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Cigarettes; Cairo, Egypt; Bow Ties; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Men; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Carpets/Rugs
  - A group portrait of men posing in a garden, some iron gates are in the background. 31.3 x 34.8 cm, 1954; cuid1358; Hamdy Sleiha, Studio Hollywood (Egypt) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Men; Group Portraits; Egypt; Arabic Writing; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Buildings; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A group portrait of five men in front of a stone building, one man holds a newspaper. 29.2 x 34.6 cm, Undated; cuid1359 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Newspapers/Magazines; Fez/Tarboush; Doors/Entrances; Buildings; Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Bow Ties; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Hats; Carpets/Rugs
  - A group portrait of twelve men. One man holds a cane (same image as ref1382). 30.4 x 36.3 cm, Undated; cuid1360 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Regional/National Dress; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Canes/Walking Sticks; Fez/Tarboush; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Outdoors; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A group portrait of twelve men. One man holds a cane. Same as ref1381. 30.4 x 36.3 cm, Undated; cuid1361 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Photographic Prints; Canes/Walking Sticks; Men; Group Portraits; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A group portrait of men, one with a walking stick, posing in front of a building with iron gates. 30.2 x 36.3 cm, Undated; cuid1362 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Egypt; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Canes/Walking Sticks; Photographic Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Buildings; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats; Carpets/Rugs
  - A group portrait of men outside a brick building. 29.8 x 35.7 cm, Undated; cuid1363 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Men; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Fez/Tarboush; Photographic Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A group portrait of men on a terrace and in a garden. 31.3 x 35.0 cm, 30 May 1950; cuid1364 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Buildings; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Men; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A group portrait of men with several different business cards around the border bearing the name 'Youssef Marco'. 32.6 x 37.7cm, Circa 1903; cuid1365 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Group Portraits; Men; Outdoors; Gelatin Silver Prints; Damietta, Egypt; Cairo, Egypt; French Writing; Officials; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Signatures
  - A group portrait of foreign soldiers in Egypt. 10.9 x 17.4 cm, Undated; cuid1366 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Women; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Parties; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Food
  - A group portrait of foreign soldiers in Egypt (same as ref1387). 10.9 x 17.4 cm, Undated; cuid1367 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Food; Men; Women; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Parties
  - A group portrait of men around a banquet table with coffee and wine. 11.5 x 17.7 cm, Undated; cuid1368 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Alcohol; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tea/Coffee; Men; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Drinks/Beverages; Events/Occasions; Waiting staff/Servers; Carpets/Rugs
  - A group portrait of women and men around a small table in a crowded room. Two women are smoking. 14.8 x 19.6 cm, 18 June 1950; cuid1369 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Furnishings; Women; Men; Events/Occasions; Smoking; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gatherings; Jewelry; Cigarettes
  - A group portrait of doctors and nurses. Four women, and seven men with mustaches. 17.0 x 22.0 cm, Undated; cuid1370 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Nurses; Doctors; Lab Coats; Facial Hair
  - A group portrait of nine women. Two women seated on the ground by a vase of flowers. 22.0 x 26.7 cm, Undated; cuid1371 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Doors/Entrances; Buildings; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Women; Group Portraits; Jewelry
  - A group portrait of men all wearing suits and tarbouches. One man wears a bow tie. 22.2 x 29.0 cm, Undated; cuid1372 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Bow Ties; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Egypt; Buildings; Fez/Tarboush; Photographic Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A group portrait of doctors, nurses, and other men and women. 26.3 x 35.2 cm, Undated; cuid1373 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Nurses; Doctors; Uniforms; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Lab Coats; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Egypt; Hats
  - A souvenir picture celebrating the end of his excellency Mr. Woller's term as the assistant general inspector of Sudan's irrigation for the Egyptian government. Taken at the general irrigation inspection authority in Khartoum. 26.9 x 32.6 cm, 31 March 1953; cuid1374; A. Kazandjian, P. O. B. 280, Khartoum (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Women; Men; Lab Coats; Arabic Writing; Group Portraits; Khartoum, Sudan; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Irrigation; Fez/Tarboush; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A group portrait of a gathering sponsored by the Ministry of Education. 30.4 x 35.5 cm, December 1949; cuid1375; Mohamed Hassan, photographer in Greater Mahalla (El-Mahalla El-Kubra, Egypt) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Men; Events/Occasions; Officials; Arabic Writing; Schools/Education; Group Portraits; El Mahalla El Kubra, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gatherings; Government; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Flags; Food; Tea/Coffee; Carpets/Rugs; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Farouk I, King of Egypt, 1920-1965
  - A group portrait of women and men, some wearing lab coats and nurse's uniforms. Names listed on front in Arabic. 31.3 x 34.8 cm, Undated; cuid1376 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Buildings; Boys; Arabic Writing; Women; Hospitals; Men; Nurses; Doctors; Group Portraits; Egypt; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Lab Coats
  - A group portrait of men and women at a gathering having a meal, two women hold champagne glasses. 30.3 x 36.1 cm, Undated; cuid1377 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Food; Furnishings; Houses; Alcohol; Parties; Food; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Women; Men; Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry
  - A series of portraits of men. Text in Arabic and English that reads 'The Clerical Staff of Cairo City Health Inspectorate and its branch offices with Dr. P.G.S. Williams, P.M.O. on the occasion of his retirement from the Egyptian Government service.' 34.0 x 40.6 cm, 1936; cuid1378 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Individual Portraits; Officials; Arabic Writing; Doctors; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Railways; Transportation; Trains; Facial Hair
  - A group portrait of men and women, posing in front of a building with large wooden doors. 34.1 x 40.7 cm, Undated; cuid1379 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Photographic Prints; Zagazig, Egypt; Women; Doors/Entrances; Men; Buildings; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Regional/National Dress; Carpets/Rugs
  - A group portrait of young women all dressed in white. 34.0 x 41.5 cm, Undated; cuid1380 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Group Portraits; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Women; Carpets/Rugs
  - A group portrait of men in suits. All men wear a tarbouche, except for one. 34.3 x 41.1 cm, Undated; cuid1381 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Bow Ties; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Egypt; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A group portrait of men, in a room with a tiled floor and patterned wallpaper at Tanta secondary school. 34.4 x 41.6 cm, 16th of April 1930; cuid1382 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Bow Ties; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Men; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Group Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Arabic Writing; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Carpets/Rugs
  - A group portrait of men in suits, all wearing tarbouches, except for two. 35.5 x 41.8 cm, Circa 1914-1922; cuid1383 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Abdin, Cairo, Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Photographic Prints; Bow Ties; Men; Hats; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Cairo, Egypt; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A group portrait of men with a small chandelier above them. 33.9 x 43.5 cm, 17 May 1923; cuid1384 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Men; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Cairo, Egypt; Furnishings; Carpets/Rugs; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Hats
  - A series of portraits of men with a crown illustrated around them. A souvenir to Abdo Effendi Sabri for his transfer from Al Mansoura to Bani Swaif. 38.7 x 48.5 cm, March 1934; cuid1385 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Studio Photography; Men; Individual Portraits; Railways; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Officials; Arabic Writing; Transportation; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Trains; Facial Hair; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A group portrait of men and women in a large hall related to the Stock Exchange (Bourse). Some of the women hold bouquets of flowers. 40.3 x 50.5 cm, Undated; cuid1386 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Egypt; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Gatherings; Group Portraits; Buildings; Women; Men; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A group portrait of five women with three children standing in front of an open door (linked ref1413). 14 x 9cm, 14 June 1931; cuid1387 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Group Portraits; Houses; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Greek Writing; Girls; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Buildings; Jewelry
  - Portrait of a woman lying down on a bed of flowers and branches. Two children visible in the background (linked ref1412). 9 x 14cm, 14 June 1931; cuid1388 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Buildings; Greek Writing; Houses; Egypt; Children; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Photographic Prints
  - A group portrait of men posing with violins and an oud. 20.0 x 25.2 cm, Undated; cuid1389 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Photographic Prints; Musicians; Oud; Gelatin Silver Prints; Doors/Entrances; Men; Group Portraits; Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Musical Instruments; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats; Carpets/Rugs
  - A group portrait of men wearing suits and tarbouches, posing in a room with various pictures hanging on the wall. 24.0 x 30.1 cm, Undated; cuid1390 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Egypt; Bow Ties; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Hats
  - A group portrait of four men, three in a vehicle with a pyramid and sphinx behind them. 28.9 x 34.2 cm, Undated; cuid1391 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    The Great Sphinx of Giza; Giza, Egypt; Cars/Trucks; Fez/Tarboush; Police; Uniforms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Transportation; Weapons; Photographic Prints; Pyramids; Men; Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Hats
  - A group portrait of fourteen women in a courtyard. 30.4 x 36.2 cm, Undated; cuid1392 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Buildings; Egypt; Jewelry; Carpets/Rugs
  - A group portrait of men and one woman, four men wear white overalls and the woman wears a nurse's veil. 35.8 x 42.2cm, Undated; cuid1393 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Regional/National Dress; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Nurses; Doctors; Uniforms; Buildings; Doors/Entrances; Fez/Tarboush; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Lab Coats; Carpets/Rugs; Facial Hair; Egypt; Hats
  - Alexandria Amiri hospital, Internal medicine department. 35.8 x 42.4 cm, January 1940; cuid1394 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Buildings; Arabic Writing; Uniforms; Alexandria, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Nurses; Women; Hospitals; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Lab Coats; Facial Hair
  - A series of five portraits of men and young men. Second photo shows two people, and third is tinted red. 18.9 x 53.7 cm, Undated; cuid1395 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Egypt; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Men; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Boys; Fez/Tarboush; Smoking; Cigarettes; Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Children; Hats
  - A series of five portraits of women. 20.0 x 53.7 cm, Undated; cuid1396 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Costumes; Swords/Knives; Gelatin Silver Prints; Weapons; Head Covers/Veils; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Egypt; Women; Individual Portraits; Bags/Purses; Fur Garments; Guns; Jewelry; Photographic Prints
  - A series of five portraits of three women and two girls. Second photograph has parts tinted red. 20.0 x 55.7 cm, 1927; cuid1397 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Studio Photography; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Women; Girls; Individual Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Painted Backdrops; Children
  - A series of four portraits of men and one presumably missing photo. 18.9 x 54.0 cm, Undated; cuid1398 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Facial Hair; Egypt; Studio Photography; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Hats
  - A series of five portraits of men. 19.2 x 54.3 cm, Undated; cuid1399 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Men; Egypt; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Fez/Tarboush; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats